Roman Ostash

Software Developer

New York, USA

Software Developer experienced in creating full-stack JavaScript applications with React, Redux, Node, Express, Apollo Client and GraphQL.

Excellent communicator and team player, with the ability to function effectively in the conditions of high stress.

Responsible and dedicated professional, motivated to seek and gain new knowledge and experience.

Contacts

roman@ostash.dev ostash.dev github.com/Romacoding linkedin.com/in/roman-ostash twitter.com/ostash

Skills

Clojure: Leiningen, ClojureScript, Reagent.

JavaScript: ES2019, TypeScript, Node, Deno.

CSS: styled-components, Sass, CSS Modules.

Frameworks: React, Redux, Gatsby, Vue.

Testing: Jest, React Testing Library, Mocha.

Databases: PostgreSQL, Firebase, MongoDB.

Software: Visual Studio Code, Webpack, Git, Docker, npm, AWS,

Jira.

Work experience

St. Vladimir's Seminary, Yonkers, NY April 2019 to present

System Support Specialist

- Created dynamic, responsive, attractive and functional websites using modern JavaScript React library and Wordpress CMS.
- Effectively used modern web practices to ensure cross-browser and cross-device compatibility and to increase user engagement.
- Extensively utilized GitHub for version control and collaboration.

The Orthodox Church in America, Syosset, NY

November 2012 to April 2019

Administrative Assistant / Web Developer

- Successfully developed company's websites: design, technical support and analytics (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Google Analytics).
- Implemented performance optimization, SEO best practices and security fixes for the positive user experience and satisfaction.
- Increased online giving revenue and recurring donations by integrating payment tools (PayPal and Stripe).

Technowind, Sambir, Ukraine February 2008 to August 2009

Computer Systems Engineer

- Effectively performed server/client administration and multi- platform configuration (Mac, Linux and Windows).
- Successfully provided ticket support with desktop software, user accounts, network issues via phone, email and in person.
- Accurately managed assets inventory database and created detailed technical documentation and guides for the users.

Rabada, Sambir, Ukraine March 2003 to January 2008

Software Engineer

- Implemented new and configured existing modules to categorize products, generate sales reports.
- Increased performance with use of caching techniques, and performed optimization of queries and stored procedures in SOL.
- Successfully integrated payment services into the POS architecture and performed end user training.

Education

Lviv University of Trade and Economics, Master's degree in Finance.

St Tikhon's Orthodox Theological Seminary, Master's degree in Theology.

Languages

English (fluent), Russian (fluent), Ukrainian (native) and Polish (basic).